Hello, English learners, and welcome
back to English Pod. My name is Marco.
And I'm Erica. How are you, Erica?
Marco, I'm doing really well today.
You're excited. Uh-huh, we've
got a great lesson for everyone.
Yes, we have a really common situation where
we're going to use real English, right?
Yep, everyday English,
English that people really use.
And that's what we
want you to learn.
What are we talking
about today specifically?
Today, we have a really common situation
that is a little bit embarrassing.
All right, an
embarrassing situation.
So let's listen to the
dialogue for the first time,
and it's going
to be kind of fast.
Yeah, but don't worry if you
don't understand everything,
because after 10 minutes,
you'll understand everything.
Perfect. All
right, let's listen.
Nick, how's it going? Oh, hey!
What are you doing in this neighborhood?
Do you live around here? Actually,
my office is right around the corner.
It was great to meet you
last week at the conference.
I really enjoyed our
conversation about
foreign investment. Yeah,
yeah, it was really interesting.
You know, I'm
in a bit of a hurry,
but here's my card. We should definitely
meet up again and continue our discussion.
Sure, you still have my
contact details, right?
You know what? This is really embarrassing,
but your name has just slipped my mind.
Can you remind me? Sure,
my name is Anna Ferris. Don't
worry about it. It
happens to me all the time.
I'm terrible with names too.
Wow, Nick forgot her name.
Yeah, that's happened
to me a couple of times,
and I'm going to tell you
about it a little bit later.
Okay. All right, well, let's start
with our three language takeaways.
Language takeaway. So our first word on our
language takeaway is in a bit of a hurry.
In a bit of a hurry. In a bit of a hurry.
So Nick was in a hurry. Yeah, that's right.
This is a great phrase.
So let's listen to
three examples of how
you can use this phrase.
Example one. Can you drive faster?
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
Example two.
I can't talk right now.
I'm in a bit of a hurry.
Example three.
Okay, so it's clear now.
Basically, it means that
you don't have time.
You're moving really
quickly. Okay, perfect.
Now let's look at our second
language takeaway word
and its contact details,
contact details, contact
details, contact details. So
what are your contact details?
Basically, this is the information you
can find on your business card. All right.
So we have like our name,
our telephone number, your
email address, perhaps
your mobile phone number.
So all the useful
information so people can get
in touch with you. Yeah, so
people can phone you or email you.
Okay, so contact details. Great.
Okay. So our third
word is slipped my mind.
Slip my mind. Slipped
my mind. Slipped my mind.
So this is a funny phrase.
It's kind of strange, right?
Yes, slipped my mind.
It sounds very weird.
Exactly. Okay, so now
we're going to listen to two
examples of this phrase. Try and see if you
can figure out what it means. Example one.
I'm sorry. I forgot to respond
to your email. Just slip my mind.
Example two. Don't you
know what day it is today?
Oh, it's your birthday. It
completely slipped my mind.
Ah, so slipped my mind is like
I forgot you forgot something.
Uh-huh. So
accidentally, right. Okay,
great. Now it's time
for putting it together.
Putting it together. All
right, Erica, why don't you
tell our listeners what
putting it together is?
Well, putting it together helps
you put language together.
It helps you be more
fluent by knowing
how words fit together.
Great. So let's look at
our first phrase today and
it's around here, around
here, around here,
around here. So this is like
close by, close by, right?
I can say, for example,
is there a bank around
here? Yeah, yeah.
Um, so that's, is there a
bank close to here? Exactly.
Now, this phrase around
here, we can change it a
little bit and it means
something a little bit different.
Right. I could say,
Marco, there's a great
restaurant right
around the corner. Right.
And that would mean there is a
great restaurant on the other street.
Yep. Around the
corner. Yep. Great.
Or we have another
example. We can say around
there around there.
Right. So for example, I
can say, uh, Los
Angeles is a great city.
I used to live around there. So
you used to live near Los Angeles.
Exactly. All right. It's a really good
phrase and it's really common. Yeah.
Now our next phrase and
putting it together is terrible with,
terrible with, terrible
with, terrible with.
So we have a couple of
examples that will show you
how this phrase
works. Example one.
You're terrible with numbers.
You can't even remember
your own telephone
number. Example two.
I am terrible with directions.
I'm always getting lost.
Example three. I'm terrible with faces.
I can never remember what people look like.
Wow. I understand that I'm
also terrible with numbers.
I can barely add two plus two.
Well, yeah, I guess not
everyone is a numbers person.
I'm terrible with faces.
I sometimes forget
what people look like.
Really? Yeah. Uh oh.
So I think it's time now for us to
listen to our dialogue a second time.
Okay. This time the dialogue will be a
little bit slower. Right. So try and listen
for some of the words
we've just talked about.
Nick, how's it going? Oh,
hey. What are you doing in
this neighborhood?
Do you live around here?
Actually, my office is
right around the corner.
It was great to meet you
last week at the conference.
I really enjoyed our
conversation about foreign
investment. Yeah. Yeah.
It was really interesting.
You know, I'm in a bit
of a hurry, but here's my
card. We should definitely
meet up again and
continue our discussion.
Sure. You still have my
contact details,
right? You know what?
This is really embarrassing,
but your name has just slipped
my mind. Can you remind me?
Sure. My name is Anna Ferris.
Don't worry about
it. It happens to me
all the time. I'm terrible with names too.
So it's more clear now. You can understand
a lot better, right?
Yeah, that's true. Great.
So now it's time for us
to take a look at fluency
builder. Fluency builder.
So with fluency builder,
we take some very simple
phrases and show you
how you can be more fluent or
how you can sound more native.
Yeah. Great. In the
beginning of the dialogue,
Anna said, Nick, how's it going?
Yeah, this is a great phrase.
It sounds really,
really natural.
You know, sometimes I hear
students say, how are you?
Or how are you doing?
Those are two great
phrases, but this one
sounds really, really natural.
It just sounds more
casual. Yeah, let's listen
again to that phrase
from the dialogue.
How's it going? How's it
going? Great. So next time that
you find a friend on the
street, you can just say,
Hey, how's it going? Yeah.
So Marco, have you ever
forgotten someone's
name? Yeah, it's happened
to me a couple of times.
And actually the most
embarrassing situation was
that I forgot a family members.
No, a family member's name.
We had like a family reunion.
And there were a lot of
ants and uncles and cousins
that I hadn't seen in a while.
And I just forgot one
of my uncle's names.
And that was, oh, that's
pretty embarrassing. Yeah.
So what did you do?
Well, I had to ask one of
my other cousins, like,
hey, it was that guy.
He's like, Oh, that's uncle
John. I'm like, Oh, man,
I totally forgot. Yeah. So
it was really embarrassing
because I didn't
know what to call him.
So I just called him uncle
because I didn't know his name.
Hi, uncle. Yeah. Oh, yeah.
So when that happens
to me when I'm in a
business setting, sometimes
what I do is I ask
for someone's card.
Yeah, that's the good technique.
Yeah. Or sometimes I might
ask them to write down
their email because usually
their full name is spelled
out in their email address.
So that's my trick when I
forgotten someone's name.
That's a good trick.
And I guess a lot
of our listeners can
take your advice on that.
Okay. So I think it's
time for us to listen to our
dialogue one more time
this time at natural speed.
Nick, how's it going?
Oh, hey, what are you
doing in this neighborhood?
Do you live around here?
Actually, my office is
right around the corner.
It was great to meet you
last week at the conference.
I really enjoyed our conversation
about foreign investment.
Yeah, yeah, it was
really interesting.
You know, I'm in a bit of
a hurry, but here's my card.
We should definitely meet up
again and continue our discussion.
Sure. You still have my
contact details, right?
You know what? This is really embarrassing,
but your name has just slipped my mind.
Can you remind me? Sure.
My name is Anna Ferris.
Don't worry about it. It
happens to me all the time.
I'm terrible with names
too. Well, I hope that
you've all enjoyed our
lesson for today and
remember to check out
our website at EnglishPod.
com where you can find
a lot of other resources
and you can leave all your
questions and comments.
Yeah, Marco and I
are always on the site,
so we're happy to answer
all of your questions.
Exactly. So now it's time
for us to say goodbye.
[Music]